Minutes of the Executive Council of AFL, Pt. 2 on Microfilm 5918 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Minutes 1932-1935 (Reel 4)
  - 0121. Meeting Minutes of October 18-27, 1932. 93 pages., 2 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: Carpenters agreement with Machinists; Communist conference stumps American Federation of Labor convention; child labor; convict labor; five-day workweek; immigration restriction; injunction relief legislation; Kellogg-Briand Pact; old age security legislation; Pan American Federation of Labor; depression relief principles; unemployment; unemployment insurance; unemployment policies; Volstead Act modification; workmen's compensation; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; American Federation of Government Employees; American Federation of Labor requests unemployment conference with Herbert Hoover; railroad workers pension legislation; Theatrical Stage Employees and Motion Picture Machine Operators protection against dual unionism.
  - 0214. Meeting Minutes of November 20 and December 3, 1932. 34 pages., 3 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: Convict labor; Sleeping Car Porters injunction fight; shorter workday and workweek legislation; Daniel Tobin candidacy for secretary of labor; women and children in industry; bill to prohibit federal purchase of sweatshop products; women's auxiliaries in American Federation of Labor; workmen's compensation.
  - 0248. Meeting Minutes of April 20-May 2, 1933. 114 pages., 4 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: Brewery Workers jurisdiction dispute with Engineers and Teamsters; Bridge and Structural Iron Workers corruption case; Chain Store Employees organization drive; Commercial Telegraphers organizing drive among postal employees; five-day workweek; six-hour day legislation; Nazi treatment of German trade unions; Marine Engineers Beneficial Association charter application; National Association of Master Mechanics and Foremen of Navy Yards charter application; American Federation of Labor opposition to minimum wage legislation; Federated Motion Picture Studio Crafts recognition battle; naval appropriations; railroad legislation; Executive Council visit to President Roosevelt; recognition of Russia; Sleeping Car Porters injunction case; women's auxiliaries.
  - 0362. Meeting Minutes of September 6-15, 1933. 96 pages., 5 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor organizing campaign in federal labor unions; Federal Bankruptcy Act; Firemen and Oilers jurisdiction award over Brewery Firemen; Machinists jurisdiction dispute with Carpenters Union; Executive Council visit with President Roosevelt; six-hour day legislation; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0458. Meeting Minutes of October 1, 8, and 11, 1933. 36 pages., 6 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: Amalgamated Clothing Workers charter issued; nationalization of banks; Communist interference with American Federation of Labor convention; resolution on Father Charles E. Coughlin; policies regarding federal labor unions; Panama Canal Commission; National Recovery Act; discrimination against older workers; organizing drive among African Americans.
  - 0494. Meeting Minutes of January 23-February 1934. 118 pages., 7 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: Brewery Workers jurisdiction dispute with Teamsters, Engineers, and Firemen; cigar making industry code; company unions amendment to Section 7-A National Recovery Act; resolution on Father Charles E. Coughlin; Fur Workers representation dispute; Ladies Garment Workers jurisdiction dispute with Textile Workers; unemployment relief in New York, New York; Steel Workers protest against Weirton Steel Company; Theatrical Stage Employees; jurisdiction over motion picture machine operators; unemployment insurance; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0612. Meeting Minutes of May 2-11, 1934. 104 pages., 8 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor organizing drive; Automobile Workers organizing campaign; Firemen dispute with Engineers; Garment Workers jurisdiction dispute with Textile Workers; paper industry organizing campaign; resolution on George W. Perkins; Wagner-Connery Labor Disputes Act; women's auxiliaries; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0716. Meeting Minutes of August 6-17, 1934. 81 pages., 9 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: Automobile Workers Federal Labor Unions; Sleeping Car Porters charter application; women's auxiliaries; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0797. Meeting Minutes of September 28-October 14, 1934. 121 pages., 10 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; appeals of Carpenters, Bricklayers, and Electrical Workers to Building Trades Department; Agricultural and Cannery Workers Union reduction in dues; anti-union laws; Boulder Dam labor conditions; company unions; convict labor; employment agencies; Federal Emergency Relief Administration employment requirements; labor standards on government contracts; Federal Housing Act; immigration law modification; African American organizers; racketeering resolution; rubber workers unemployment; Sleeping Car Porters application; thirty-hour workweek; Timber Workers organizing; Textile Workers strike.
  - 0918. Meeting Minutes of January 29-February 14, 1935. 116 pages., 11 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: Automobile Workers organizing drive; Blacksmiths protest American Federation of Labor organizing infringements; Firemen jurisdiction dispute with engineers; Gas Workers charter application; Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers protest Anaconda Company agreement with Metal Trades Department; Carpenters jurisdiction over Saw Mill and Timber Workers; Textile Workers program; Tobacco Trades Council petition regarding codes; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
- Minutes 1935-1936 (Reel 5)
  - 0001. Meeting Minutes of January 29-February 14, 1935 (continued). 226 pages., 1 (Reel 5)
    Major Topics: Executive Council meeting with Colonel Daniel McCormack, Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization; radicalism in the labor movement; Automobile Workers organizing drive; Blacksmiths protest American Federation of Labor organizing infringements; Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; Building Trades controversy; Child Labor Amendment; Fascist movement activities in United States; Sidney Hillman and National Recovery Administration administration; immigration legislation amendments; International Labor Office; prevailing wages in federal relief employment; Marine Shipbuilders charter application; Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers protest Anaconda Company agreement with Metal Trades Department; Amalgamated Clothing Workers; Executive Council meeting with President Roosevelt; Radio Workers charter application; Sleeping Car Porters jurisdiction dispute with Sleeping Car Conductors; Steel Workers organizing campaign; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0227. Meeting Minutes of April 30-May 7, 1935. 189 pages., 2 (Reel 5)
    Major Topics: Automobile Workers organization; Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; Building Service Employees jurisdictional applications; Catholic University of America chair in social economics; Father Charles E. Coughlin invites American Federation of Labor to participate in National Union for Social Justice; Firemen and Oilers dispute with Textile Workers; Dubinsky report on Firemen and Oilers dispute with Textile Workers; Dubinsky report on International Labor Office; industrial organization in mass production industries; Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers protest Metal Trades Department agreement with Anaconda Company; Molders amalgamation with Foundry Workers; American Federation of Labor conference with President Roosevelt; Rubber Workers charter application; Steel Workers insurgent movement; Wagner labor disputes bill; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0416. Meeting Minutes of June 6-7, 1935. 47 pages., 3 (Reel 5)
    Major Topics: Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; Building Trades Department, internal controversy; Father Charles E. Coughlin communication; Supreme Court decision invalidating National Recovery Act; Robert F. Wagner meeting with Executive Council.
  - 0463. Meeting Minutes of August 5-16, 1935. 128 pages., 4 (Reel 5)
    Major Topics: Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; Building Trades Department, internal controversy; anti-Communist amendment to American Federation of Labor convention; injunction relief laws; Child Labor Amendment; industrial organization in mass production industries; National Labor Relations Board; National Recovery Act invalidation; unemployment relief; National Youth Administration; International Labor Office; racketeering investigation in New York; Sleeping Car Porters jurisdiction; American Federation of Labor Special Committee on Colored Workers; Social Security Board; Theatrical Stage Employees jurisdiction extension; Workers Education Bureau; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0591. Meeting Minutes of October 5-6, 12, and 20-21, 1935. 150 pages., 5 (Reel 5)
    Major Topics: Automobile Workers organization; American Federation of Labor resolution regarding Communists; Thomas E. Dewey racketeering investigation; American Federation of Labor resolution on injunctions; labor and depression relief legislation; anti-lynching bill; Communist activity in Minneapolis labor movement; Mooney case expenses; Special Committee Report on Negro Workers; organizing drive among African Americans; Scottsboro case; organizing drive in southern states; Steel Workers organizing drive; American Federation of Labor legislative activities; Seattle, Washington, Labor Council suspension of Brewery Workers; American Federation of Teachers investigation; National Youth Administration.
  - 0741. Meeting Minutes of January 15-29, 1936. 238 pages., 6 (Reel 5)
    Major Topics: Automobile Workers organization; International Labor Office; British Trades Union Congress; Child Labor Amendment; Congress of Industrial Organizations; amendment to United States Constitution to limit judicial review of legislation; Arkansas Tenant Farmers organization; immigration legislation; Iron and Steel Workers organization; American Federation of Labor resolution on Kohler Company; resignation of John L. Lewis from Executive Council; Metal Trades Department dispute with Oil Field Workers; organization of Lumber Workers; American Federation of Labor critical report on National Civic Federation; Radio Workers charter application denied; Rubber Workers constitution; Sleeping Car Porters charter; Tampa, Florida, floggings of labor organizers reported by Norman Thomas; women's auxiliaries; Workers Education Bureau; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
- Minutes 1936 (Reel 6)
  - 0001. Meeting Minutes of May 5-20, 1936. 297 pages., 1 (Reel 6)
    Major Topics: Sheet Metal Workers jurisdiction dispute with Machinists; Automobile Workers organization; Brewery Workers dispute with Seattle Central Labor Union; civil service qualifications; Congress of Industrial Organizations; convict labor legislation; Flat Glass Workers jurisdiction; American Federation of Labor opposition to Frazier-Lemke Act; International Federation of Trade Unions; American Federation of Labor Legal Defense Department; American Federation of Labor legislative program; Pan American Federation of Labor; Social Security Act administration; Steel Workers organizing campaign; American Federation of Teachers; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; unemployment immigration restriction; injunction relief to supplement National Labor Relations Act; subversive activities.
  - 0298. Meeting Minutes of July 8-15, 1936. 272 pages., 2 (Reel 6)
    Major Topics: Building Service Employees jurisdiction extension; Congress of Industrial Organizations; Metal Trades Department charges against Congress of Industrial Organizations; Ladies Garment Workers affiliation with Congress of Industrial Organizations; Mooney-Billings Defense Fund; Seamen's International Union and Pacific Coast maritime dispute; Textile Workers affiliation with Congress of Industrial Organizations; American Federation of Labor suspension of Congress of Industrial Organizations unions.
  - 0570. Meeting Minutes of August 3-5, 1936. 84 pages., 3 (Reel 6)
    Major Topics: Congress of Industrial Organizations; Electrical Workers charges against Congress of Industrial Organizations; Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers relationship to Congress of Industrial Organizations; International Typographical Union relationship with Congress of Industrial Organizations; Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen jurisdiction expansion; Metal Trades Department charges against Congress of Industrial Organizations; Printing Trades dispute with Lithographers; American Federation of Labor suspension of Congress of Industrial Organizations unions; Wisconsin Federation of Labor resolution regarding Congress of Industrial Organizations.
  - 0654. Meeting Minutes of October 8-21, 1936. 233 pages., 4 (Reel 6)
    Major Topics: American Newspaper Guild strike at Seattle Post- Intelligencer; Amalgamated Clothing Workers disputes with United Garment Workers; Cloth Hat, Cap, and Millinery Workers resolution on Congress of Industrial Organizations; Machinists resolution on Congress of Industrial Organizations; Congress of Industrial Organizations activities in Toledo, Ohio; Dubinsky resignation as vice president of American Federation of Labor; Building Service Employees jurisdiction expansion; American Federation of Labor relations with Federal Labor Unions; Automobile Workers and American Federation of Labor; convict labor; civil service; health insurance; housing; European labor; National Labor Relations Board; Pan American Federation of Labor; public education; Puerto Rico; depression relief; Social Security Act; Steel Workers organizing campaign; unemployment; American Federation of Teachers; technological changes; Hutcheson resignation as vice president of American Federation of Labor; Indiana State Federation of Labor endorsement of Farmer-Labor Party; International Federation of Trade Unions; International Typographical Union relations with Congress of Industrial Organizations; Lithographers dispute with Printing Trades Unions; United States Supreme Court decision on National Recovery Administration; American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees charter; Walsh-Healey minimum wage bill; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0887. Meeting Minutes of November 14-15 and 28-29, 1936. 64 pages., 5 (Reel 6)
    Major Topics: Butte, Montana, Central Labor Union charter application; Congress of Industrial Organizations; Brewery Workers resolution on Congress of Industrial Organizations; company unions; convict labor; housing; immigration legislation; International Federation of Trade Unions; Marine Engineers Beneficial Association; motion picture industry labor agreement; American Newspaper Guild trike in Seattle; Puerto Rico and Wagner Labor Relations Act; depression relief qualifications; labor espionage; limitation of power of United States Supreme Court; vigilante violence; Walsh-Healey minimum wage bill; Filipino exclusion; seamen's legislation; occupational disease; workmen's compensation.
- Minutes 1937-1938 (Reel 7)
  - 0001. Meeting Minutes of February 8-19, 1937. 247 pages., 1 (Reel 7)
    Major Topics: Agricultural, Packing House, and Cannery Workers union; Butte, Montana, Central Labor Union application; Congress of Industrial Organizations; Congress of Industrial Organizations relations with Central Labor Unions; Communist activities in labor movement; Gallup, Mexico, Miners situation; General Motors strike; federal (Guffey) coal bill; Hotel and Restaurant Workers jurisdiction expansion; General Hugh S. Johnson attack on American Federation of Labor; Machinists dispute with Tobacco Workers; Masters, Mates, and Pilots dispute with Longshoremen; Meat Cutters and Butchers Workmen jurisdiction expansion; Metal Trades Department hearing on Congress of Industrial Organizations activities; minimum wage legislation; motion picture industry agreement; African American labor organizers; Ladies Pocketbook and Novelty Workers charters; white collar workers organization; Works Progress Administration workers organization; Seamen's International Union insurgent challenge; United States Supreme Court president reorganization plan; Teamsters jurisdictional expansion; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0248. Meeting Minutes of April 19-22, 1937. 51 pages., 2 (Reel 7)
    Major Topics: Congress of Industrial Organizations; Cleveland Federation of Labor; report on Congress of Industrial Organizations; Georgia Federation of Labor resolution on American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations; Massachusetts Federation of Labor organizing drive; minimum wage legislation; International Textile conference.
  - 0299. Meeting Minutes of May 23 and 26-30, 1937. 156 pages., 3 (Reel 7)
    Major Topics: Agricultural, Packing House, and Cannery Workers charter application; Aluminum Workers affiliation with Congress of Industrial Organizations; Chicago Federation of Labor; Congress of Industrial Organizations; Georgia Federation of Labor relations with Congress of Industrial Organizations; American Federation of Labor Marine Trades Department; Progressive Miners charter application; Street and Electric Railway Employees dispute with Transit Workers Union in New York, New York; International Typographical Union relations with Congress of Industrial Organizations; Teamsters jurisdiction extension to warehousemen; Welders charter application denied; Pacific Coast Longshoremen dispute with Teamsters over warehousemen; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0455. Meeting Minutes of August 21-September 2, 1937. 216 pages., 4 (Reel 7)
    Major Topics: Brewery Workers suit against American Federation of Labor and Teamsters; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress; Constitutional amendments; Building Service Employees jurisdiction extension; exclusion of alien workers; age discrimination; injunction relief legislation; child labor; Congress of Industrial Organizations; convict labor; hours of work for women and minors; housing legislation; industrial homework; anti-lynching bill; Progressive Miners Union; Pan American Federation of Labor; Puerto Rico Free Federation of Workingmen; Railroad Employees Retirement Law; sit-down strikes; social security; wages and hours legislation; International Federation of Trade Unions; International Labor Office; Congress of Industrial Organizations organization in lumber industry; maritime organizations; Congress of Industrial Organizations activity in Minneapolis Central Labor Union; Quarry Workers jurisdiction dispute with Teamsters, and Hod Carriers and Engineers; Seamen's International Union reorganization; West Virginia State Federation of Labor; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0671. Meeting Minutes of October 3-4, 9, and 13-16, 1937. 109 pages., 5 (Reel 7)
    Major Topics: Building Service employees jurisdiction dispute with Hotel and Restaurant Employees; cannery industry organizing campaign; Congress of Industrial Organizations activities in northwest lumber industry and Pacific Coast maritime industry; American Federation of Labor "peace conference" with Congress of Industrial Organizations; American Federation of Labor Defense Fund; Federal Labor Unions tax reductions and suspensions; housing; anti-lynching bill; Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers charter application; National Labor Relations Board; African American organizers; old age pensions; Progressive Miners charter application; Puerto Rico political situation; wages and hours legislation.
  - 0780. Meeting Minutes of December 3-4, 1937. 18 pages., 6 (Reel 7)
    Major Topics: Marine Engineers Beneficial Association jurisdiction dispute with Operating Engineers; wages and hours legislation.
  - 0798. Meeting Minutes of January 24-February 8, 1938. 263 pages., 7 (Reel 7)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor tax assessments; Blacksmiths jurisdiction dispute with Machinists; Building Service Employees dispute with Hotel and Restaurant Employees; Bridge and Structural Iron Workers dispute with Teamsters and Engineers; report on Congress of Industrial Organizations; organizing drive ta Ford Motor Company; Wagner Housing Bill provision for prevailing wage rates; Japanese aggression in China; wages and hours legislation; Building Trades agreement with Maintenance of Way Employees; Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers charter revocation; Progressive Miners of America; United Mine Workers charter revocation; social security legislation; unemployment; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
- Minutes 1938-1939 (Reel 8)
  - 0001. Meeting Minutes of April 25-May 5, 1938. 211 pages., 1 (Reel 8)
    Major Topics: Public works and appropriations bills; Bakery and Confectioner Workers jurisdiction expansion; Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; Building Trades dispute in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania; Congress of Industrial Organizations in Canadian Trades and Labor Congress; Seattle labor movement; wages and hours legislation; National Labor Relations Board decisions; Painters and Decorators jurisdiction expansion; Pan American Federation of Labor; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0212. Meeting Minutes of August 22-September 2, 1938. 217 pages., 2 (Reel 8)
    Major Topics: Auto Workers charters; Building and Construction Trades Department agreement with Carpenters; Congress of Industrial Organizations; Congress of Industrial Organizations status in Canadian Trades and Labor Congress; joint American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Labor Day proceedings; Dies Committee investigations; American Federation of Labor organizing drive among industrial workers; housing; Hod Carriers dispute with Quarry Workers; Hotel and Restaurant Employees dispute with Building Service Employees; report on International Federation of Trade Unions; Machinists dispute with Sheet Metal Workers; Marine Engineers Beneficial Association; Progressive Miners Union organizing drive; National Labor Relations Act, survey of decisions and administration; Packinghouse workers organizing drive; Sailors Union of the Pacific; Seamen organizing drive; Street and Electric Railway Employees jurisdiction disputes; Upholsterers jurisdiction disputes; wages and hours legislation; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0429. Meeting Minutes of October 2, 4, 8, 12, and 14, 1938. 71 pages., 3 (Reel 8)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations reconciliation proposals; Congress of Industrial Organizations representation in Canadian Trades and Labor Congress; Upholsterers Union jurisdiction disputes; Metal Trades Department organizing among shipyard workers; Seafarers International Union charter; International Seamen's Union charter revocation.
  - 0500. Meeting Minutes of January 30-February 14, 1939. 420 pages., 4 (Reel 8)